Guide to the Columbian College Alumni Association records, 1965-1993 RG0069
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Columbian College Alumni Association records
1965-1993
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Columbian College in the District of Columbia. Alumni Association
RG0069
2.6 Linear Feet
Collection includes "Arts and Sciences" newsletter, photographs, exhibits, alumni reunion weekends and homecoming materials.
Restrictions on Access
Series 1 and 3 are closed to research for 25 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the Columbian College Alumni Association.
Historical Note
The Columbian College alumni association dates back to the 1850s. Columbian College of Arts and Science is the liberal arts college within the university. Today the Columbian College Alumni Association is a part of the General Alumni Association.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include "Arts and Sciences," a newsletter for alumni of Columbian College of Arts and Sciences, photographs, "First 50 years of Columbian College" exhibit, materials relating to reunion weekends and homecoming. The collections covers the years 1965 to 1993.
Collection Organization
Organized into four series: Columbian College alumni association files; Newsletter; Alumni events; Photographs.
Events; Publications; Reunions; Photographs; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; George Washington University
- Columbian College alumni association files, 1965-1988; RG0069 Series 1; 3 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of materials relating to reunions, receptions, and events (including Phi Beta Kappa 50th anniversary, "phonathon," annual fund, poetry reading). The materials range in date from 1965-88.
  - Professor Hobbs on Halley's Comet, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poetry readings: Invitations, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - December graduates reception, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Career services for liberal arts, 01/14/1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Grace Evans: Treasure Houses of Britain, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art reception, 02/26/1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Robert Wegmann, 03/31/1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Reunion Weekend, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - New York Art Tour, 07/17/1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Program, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arts career panel, 09/20/1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dance, Music, and Theatre alumni performance, 09/26/1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Glee Club Troubadour brunch, 09/07/1986 --11/22/1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cordes on tax reform, 10/01/1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vineyard tour, 10/18/1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mayo lecture, 10/23/1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bird watching, 11/08/1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Genetic Engineering panel, 11/18/1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - New York chapter: Tax reform, 12/1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 200th Anniversary Constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Les Miserables, 01/23/1987 --01/27/1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Opening reception: Facutly arts show, 02/04/1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Matisse, 03/05/1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Baltimore event, 03/07/1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Olga Hirshorn: "On Collecting", 05/04/1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Politics and Values: Reunion, 06/06/1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cabaret, 09/16/1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Tour of Wyeth exhibit, 09/23/1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Anne Marie on "What to Do Now", 11/05/1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Miss Manners lecture, 10/16/1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - T.G. Moore regulation program, 11/18/1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Jimilu Mason "Cabriole", 12/08/1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Basketball game, 01/24/1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Fine Cuts faculty show reception, 02/10/1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Capitol Hill reception, 02/18/1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Parsifal, 03/24/1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Heimberg lunch, 03/29/1988 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 30th Anniversary, 04/23/1988 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Cats", 04/22/1988 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Sackler tour, 04/24/1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Landau dinner, 05/07/1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Boat brunch cruise, 05/15/1988 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Alumni reunion weekend, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Montpelier trip, 06/18/1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Columbian College gifts, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Linton fund, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual fund, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual fund, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Phonathon, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Phonathon, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Phonathon, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Career week programs, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Career week, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Career night, 02/01/1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conoco program, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Neejima, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chang, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - B. Diana Thompson, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Alumni schedule of events, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Winter convocation committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Graduation committee, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Commencement, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Commencement, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hoffman program: School of Government and Business Administration, 02/29/1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Proposal for Arts and Sciences newsletter, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Arts and Sciences, 09/1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Arts and Sciences, 09/1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Arts and Sciences, 01/1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Andrews AIDS file, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - AIDS material, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Alumni Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Alumni Relations, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Reunion and local programs committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Newsletter, 1986-1993; RG0069 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of Arts and Sciences, a newsletter for alumni of the Columbian College of Arts and Sciences The materials range in date from 1986-93.
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Fall
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Spring
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arts and Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Winter
- Alumni events, 1988-1990; RG0069 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of materials relating to the "First 50 years of Columbian College" exhibit, reunion weekends and homecoming, lectures, tours, and events. The materials range in date from 1988-90.
  - Les Miserables, 09/28/1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Arts Show reception, 10/15/1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Opening of "1st 50 Years of Columbian college", 10/26/1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alison Brooks lecture, 11/15/1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Robert Parris concert, 11/28/1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Intelstat tour and reception, 12/01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nutcracker, 12/17/1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pizza Nights, 01/1989 --04/1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CSC Orientation, 01/12/1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arts and Sciences Career Night, 02/07/1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Basketball, 02/11/1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cezanne lecture and tour, 02/08/1989 --02/16/1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Capitol Hill reception, 03/09/1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ardel Gallaeries, 04/06/1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Faculty--Alumni luncheon, 04/26/1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alumni Reunion weekend, 04/1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brunch and annual meeting, 04/16/1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - OAS reception, 05/31/1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Thank-you picnic, 06/06/1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Pizza Nights, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 14th Street Theatre tour, 09/23/1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1st Federal Congress exhibit and lecture, 10/03/1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Smithsonian Environmental Research Center, 10/14/1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Jeanne Miles Gallery talk, 10/28/1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ronne Award luncheon, 11/10/1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Privatization dinner meeting, 11/29/1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Trachtenberg fundraising dinner, 01/22/1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gardens on Paper, 02/01/1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Homecoming, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Dinner-theatre "Women of Manhattan", 02/15/1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Virginia Slims tournament, 02/21/1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Opening of Faculty Arts show, 03/07/1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Sodaro lecture, 03/28/1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Reunion and annual meeting, 04/1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Capitol Hill Reception, 04/19/1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Wine-tasting with David Pursglove, 05/04/1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Old Cup Steeplechase at Airlie House, 05/05/1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Merry Wives of Windsor, 06/14/1990 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Arts and Sciences, 09/1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Arts and Sciences, 01/1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Photographs, 1985-1992; RG0069 Series 4; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of photographs of functions, icluding a brunch cruise, Capitol Hill receptions, Phi Beta Kappa 50th anniversary, Ronald Reagan signing fire curtain in Lisner Auditorium. The materials range in date from 1985-92.
  - Alumni Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Black & white photos, negatives
  - Alumni College, 05/1992 --06/1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Color photos
  - Alumni Division of Arts and Sciences, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Black & white photos, inter-negatives
  - Alumni function, 1990 ca. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni reception, 12/1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Black and white photos, contact sheets, negatives
  - Brunch Cruise Photos, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Photos, contact sheets
  - Brunch, 04/16/1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Columbian College alumni executive committee, 06/1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes photo of Ronald and Nancy Reagan signing fire curtain in Lisner Auditorium
  - Capitol Hill Reception, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alumni, 1988 ca. --1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Color photos, letter
  - Columbian College Alumni Association Capitol Hill Reception, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Columbian College Alumni Association - Phi Beta Kappa 50th Anniversary, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Photos, invitations, programs
  - Cultural Arts Center-reception honoring Robert Kenny, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Negatives and contact sheets only
  - GW Report journal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Black and white photos
  - Head and shoulder shots of various people, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Contact sheets only
  - International Op article and alumni function, 1990 ca. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Contact sheets, negatives
  - Large and small black and white photos, Arts and Sciences Newsletter, 1985 ca. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Photos, correspondence, contact sheets
  - Large black and white photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lisner auditorium and Frey (?), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Contact sheets, photos